Ruben Wilson

Junior Software Engineer

London 07722160086 rwilson_connell@yahoo.com

GitHub: https://github.com/ruben-wilson

Summary

A twenty-one-year-old junior developer who is highly enthusiastic and driven. After spending nearly two years of my life preparing for the Marines, I never expected to find myself excited to start something new. Sustaining an injury in the Royal Marine's commando training, I was left with a fractured shoulder and I needed to find intellectual and physical stimulation which would fulfil my thirst for a challenge and importantly, also provide me with qualifications for a profession in which I would enjoy and be successful in.

Reconnecting with my love for technology and coding has been in itself a very rewarding journey and I am very grateful for the path that I am now on. I look forward to where this road will take me and embrace the challenge of being a part of this most exciting and innovative sector, which is technology.

Strong problem-solving and numerical skills.

 Strong communication skills, both written and verbal, developed through education and customer-facing experience gained in previous jobs.

Ability to take the initiative and work well under pressure, ensuring strict deadlines are met.

- Strong team player with effective interpersonal skills.
- Always willing and excited to continue the development of my knowledge and understanding. If that means a course or further
 qualifications, I always take this as a positive.

Project Summary

Name	Description	Tech/tools
AceBook	a Facebook clone.	node, express, jest, nodemon, hbs, mongoose and cypress
Makers BnB	a Airbnb clone.	sinatra, rackup, rspec, postgreSQL, tableplus and bootstrap
Tasks app - frontEnd Tasks app - Backend	a dynamic single page web app for planning events setting goals	node, express, jest, mongoDB and nodemon
ReefRunner	a side scroller game	JS, Phaser.js and html canvas
Chitter	A twitter clone	sinatra, rackup, rspec, postgresSQL, tableplus and postman

Experience

Makers Academy (July 2022 to October 2022)

An intensive 16-week Bootcamp focusing on:

- Pairing to problem solve efficiently, requiring teamwork and communication.
- Design concepts such as OPP, TDD, MVC and DDD.
- We used these to deliver clean code. Practised through code-reviews, using SOLID Principles, i.e Single Responsibility
- For example principles like RAG, red, amber, and green allowed me to simple but effective code like in my bank tech test
- Agile Development process to build applications dynamically and quickly in a team. Using daily stand-ups and short sprints to keep our projects adaptable and quick to deploy - this involved tools such as Trello, Miro, GitHub projects and Notion.
- Learning strategies and fundamental concepts to allow for quick learning of various languages and technologies.

Royal Marines Recruit (April 2020 - March 2022)

- First applied in October 2019 but my application was delayed due to the covid lockdown.
- Reapplied in 2020 and started the application process which involved passing:
 - A gym fitness test
 - A PRMC (an intensive week of selections at the RM's training centre in Lympstone)
 - Started phase one of training on February 21st 2022.
 - Made section IC (in command) this meant I was responsible for my room of 9. I was required to meet with Corporals and Sergeants, to relay vital information back to my section and to insure orders were carried out correctly.
 - Sustained a fractured shoulder socket after a rope climb which led to me being medically discharged.

Prestige Roofing Company (September 2019 – 2021) - Associate

- Prestige Roofing is a North Dorset independent roofing company that sub-contract jobs to multiple self-employed roofing teams.
- This was one of the jobs I undertook while training for the marines and it helped me in the marines as it had developed both my fitness
 and leadership skills.
- Activities include stripping and preparation of roof, application of various tiling and slating methods, and post-job maintenance.
- Working as part of a team, using clear and precise communication to safely complete contracted tasks.

Education:

Clayesmore School (2015 - 2018) - 9 GCSE grades achieved, 7 at grade 5 (C equivalent) or higher

• Science (Double Award) - 5 & 6, English Literature - 7, English Language - 6, Mathematics - 5 Computer Science - 6, Art -